William Jensen

Billy (he/him)

Objective

I am a self-taught software engineer with 3 years of industry experience. Currently I'm pursuing an M.S. in Computer Science at DePaul University and working as a Software Engineering Intern in video game development. I'm passionate about problem solving and designing well documented extensible codebases.

Education

M.S. | Computer Science DePaul University

Concentration: Game and Real-Time Systems

Coursework: Optimized C++, Object-Oriented Software Development, Applied Algorithms, Database Technologies, Data Structures I & II, Systems I & II, and Applied 3D Geometry

B.M. | Professional Music Berklee College of Music

Concentrations: Film Scoring and Contemporary Writing and Production

Work experience

Demiurge Studios

📛 2022-02 – present 🖓 BOSTON

Unity3D, C#, C++, and Perforce

Software Engineering Intern

- Designed and implemented gameplay features and documented in Technical Design Docs.
- Collaborated with Designers and Artist to implement new features.
- Performed routine optimization, bug fixes, and code reviews
- Coordinated with Client team to plan and implement requested features.

Autonodyne

Unity3D, C#, Java, Adobe Illustrator, and Git

Software Engineer - (2020-09 - 2021-06)

- Transitioned out of management while pursuing full-time masters degree in CS
 Software Engineering Manager (2020-01 2020-09)
- Led a team of 5 software engineers while maintaining individual contributor role
- Oversaw AR application design and implementation
- Led Android development and coordinated port from Android to Windows
 Software Engineer (2018-10 2020-01)
- Developed drone control station applications for Android and Windows
- Led design and implementation of UX optimized for Mobile platforms (tablet and phone)
- Ported UX to Windows platforms (tablet and PC)
- Developed VR application to simulate market-leading AR headsets for rapid AR prototyping

Skills

